[Music]
thanks so much for joining us well I
don't want to waste any more of your
time so I'm going to sneak off stage uh
and I'll be back at the end of your
presentation can't wait to chat more
sounds good sounds good well hello
everybody I am uh Dimitri and uh I I'm
today I'm going to speak about um the
realm just above the model it's like
when we're trying to make the model do
what we want and it's typically called
prompt engineering um I don't like the
term as much um if I reflect on it I
would prefer to call it the art and
craft of imparting wisdom uh onto LM
it's not the what of the process it's
the how of the process like if you've
ever had a privilege of uh teaching a
child uh how to program in the age of
YouTube you would notice that the
learning process has diverged dramatic
in the last decade there is plenty of
information we no longer have to impart
information on our children instead we
need to impart the wisdom is like
sorting and picking through what is
important and what is not and what is to
be ignored and what is to what is the
gem and this analogy actually applies to
LM because LMS have this massive fire
hose of knowledge they they all these
billions of parameters store something
oh technically everything but the
interesting thing is that the LMS do
need our wisdom uh and they they need
our way of thinking our way of looking
at things to Pur pursue the objectives
and fulfill the task that we want them
to do and so in some ways this is like a
this is the process right it's the
process process of imparting the the
wisdom so I'm going to uh take our
little uh breadboard um system here it's
an open source project we've been
running at Google for a little while um
and I'm going to try and build a a
podcast from topic
yeah topic and what I'm going to do is
I'm going to build a very simple
board take a happy little um model
component here and wire it
together and say you know put it into
context and let's give it a prompt and
we'll do something as simple as generate
a
podcast based on this
topic and then give it some topic so now
I I give my little
braces uh there is my topic I'm just
going to feed the topic here because
that's what one does and so now we have
a nice little model model so now we're R
this thing and say okay the topic would
be
brownan motion for example let's see
what it does let's see what kind of
things it generates it will try to
generate us some a podcast there you go
intam music host uh sound effect host
host like okay cool
guest uh interesting um but the the
thing is that it's kind of like it's
it's it's kind of generic it's not the
thing that we want because actually what
we actually want is we want to have a
bit more guidance so let's give it a bit
more guidance let's say you know give it
a system instruction and say you are a
podcast transcript writer and so what
we're actually doing is we're building a
podcast transcript so we are reminding
ANM and this is one of the interesting
things is that we're dealing with this
massive compost of knowledge or mental
models right I I prefer to not not
compost let's call it clay right and so
our job is to kind of look at what the
thing what the LM produces and shape it
the way we want it so remind it of the
knowledge that it has connect some dots
that it uh maybe doesn't have connected
meend the blind spots every LM has its
own blind spots oriented and so it's a
iterative process of kind of like a
discovery and so like for example uh a
very common thing that I insert is a
prompt that says
uh you're working as part of the team so
please don't chat back to me this is
just delivered the work product uh and
so let's try it again and uh if we try
it again we run this thing uh we will
produce uh another output and as you can
see we have now um we have science
snacks the podcast blah but again if you
read through this it's like that's right
it's like very simple uh we need a
little bit more
you know what makes podcasts interesting
is that there is always something fun
going on between the hosts and so what
we kind of need to do in this thing is
we need to say what is it that we can do
to help the model visualize this podcast
better and one thing we could do is
basically Define the setting of a
podcast and say hey model imagine that
this podcast is about physics uh and
this is the topic is the Brownian motion
and uh the host is you know Bob and Jill
and Bob is uh tired and Jill is cranky
or I don't know whatever whatever those
things are but like the good news is
that we don't actually have to do this
by ourselves we can just uh take a happy
little model again um and add it to this
to this thing and just um create another
system instruction and say you know what
you
are a creative writer your work product
is a detailed description of a podcast
setting that you imagined and so the
podcast will reveal U we'll discuss the
information provided in context so what
we're doing is we're actually asking llm
to to design us a podcast experience so
design the setting for the podcast and
so we will probably call this instead of
model we'll call it design podcast set
right and so and one of the things is
that the source of t that might be going
on well of course we need to make sure
that so these two lines are really
interesting because now we're not just
creating a generic vanilla podcast we're
actually adding some interesting stuff
again what we're doing is we're tickling
just the right parts of the llm to give
it the wisdom to say look a good podcast
typically has attenion between the
between the hosts and we're going to
have two hosts and they have have names
they're not going to have generic things
and then they're going to have quirks
and strengths and weaknesses and so and
what what this allows us to do is that
allows us to build a much more
interesting presentation right because
at this point you you have uh so let's
let's go ahead and get the stuff done
design podcast setting and uh we're
going to give it a topic as a context
conversation um of this thing right um
and so the next thing we're going to do
is we're going to say hey in this uh
prompt and this
setting and so what we're going to do is
now we're going to add setting to see
right here we're going to add
setting to this situation to this to
this to this what is
this right podcast
right so at this point now we have two
interesting things going on right we
have two model cods CH changed in a
really interesting way we give it a
topic we say this is whatever the topic
it is it designs the podcast setting
then it supplies that podcast setting
along with the topic to write the the
transcript let's see what
happens Brown in motion let's let's keep
the thing and so now it goes off and
starts creating a podcast setting right
it it builds out the uh the the the
actual imagines the the what this
podcast is about what's the name and so
again look at this we have uh now we
have Anna and Benny we have two
different things uh you know see they
have like they have attention now now
there's interesting stuff going on
they're they're actually having a
conversation right you're not just
having a generic blah blah blah blah
blah blah blah suddenly these people are
in conversation with each other there is
tension between them there is
exasperation you know and it's like it's
one of those things that you go and say
holy moly suddenly we've imparted wisdom
into the um into this into this system
uh we've built an AI system effectively
instead of just one prompt because what
we've done is we've said hey before
going on with the writing of the podcast
imagine what the podcast setting might
be first
and make this a separate step of the
process so that it feels like when
you're starting to generate the the
podcast you're starting from scratch
you're starting from uh this this this
raw information that comes into you and
so it's it's a really interesting
process here is because there is many
many problems where um if you look at
the kind of Point cloud of the good
results you just want to nail The Target
just precisely for example when you have
customer support when you have llms
doing work that is that must result in
Fairly predictable but flexible outcomes
there are also many problems where that
that point cloud of good is diffused and
actually interesting things occur in the
edges of these things when there is a
tension between hosts you don't want a
boring podcast you want interesting
podcast an interesting podcast usually
will produce results that are somewhat
um maybe unusual there might be
something going on there that is that
like a tension between the hosts and
things like this and that's like multi-
prompt systems or AI systems typically
are really good when you're trying to
harvest the value in that diffusion
diffus space and so anything that if
you're writing songs if you're making
music any creative task any task that
when you're trying to entertain Delight
somebody in a way that is low stakes and
interesting suddenly the AI systems go
like holy moly this is our this is our
thing we know how to do this and so um
the next thing we can do is say like
okay this isn't neat but how do we give
a little bit more oomph to this AI
system and uh one of the ways we can do
this is we can actually give it a um
let's see we can give it a a researcher
so we can instead of let's take our
happy little model one more time
and uh give this um Model
A do some
research because you know what it's nice
that LM knows all the things about
podcasts or or brown in motion because
all of the parameter parametric
knowledge is there but would would be
really cool if we could make it do some
actual grounded research right and so
again this is a mo this is a mode in
which you're trying to kind of like go
into the space of how do we make AI do
reasoning one of the interesting things
is like when we look at reasoning we
assume that this is a
natural uh thing that humans do but if
you think about it and reason about it
uh humans have lived without reasoning
much longer than they lived with
reasoning uh reasoning is a fairly
modern invention and it's a scientific
or technological breakthrough of
breaking down problems into tasks and
are reasoning or you know thinking
through this in steps and figuring out
how to solve a problem in a way that
takes a more complex problem and turns
into a much more palatable things and so
reasoning is something that I believe
and like as previous speaker was
indicating we can definitely teach LMS
because it is not a natural innate
ability of humans it is a thing that we
are taught in school and this is what or
by parents or whatever wherever we are
and so it's let's teach it to do some
research okay so we're start we're going
to start with
uh you're a researcher your job is to
use the provided topic to produce raw
research that will be later used to
produce the podcast you are tested with
finding as much relevant information as
possible okay so we're going to
now uh make it examine a conversation
context so far and come up come up with
just one step to produce used to report
using the conversation context as the
guide of State Sten so far in outcomes
recorded we also do this usual chat chat
Clause because we don't want it to talk
uh back and say what do you think this
is better and things like this and so
and again we're going to try to think of
it
as just one step we're going to answer
two questions we're asking it to reason
first we're asking your am am I done
looking back on the conversation if you
have three Five results you are done
second we're going to ask it to provide
a response and then response is going to
be a thought I have to think about what
is this the right step and what is the
description of what we'll do next um
we'll do in plain English and then we'll
ask it to invoke some
tools uh there is a a bunch of tools
that I can uh make available and um I'm
going to use of them so I'm going to
take um
I'm going to take search Wikipedia
perhaps as one tool I'm going to take um
Google custom search as one tool because
you know we want to give it all kinds of
nice tools to we're going to give it get
web page content as a tool and we're
going to give it
uh what would be a good one oh um places
right so we we're going to give it some
Google Google Places API so we can look
at these things and also notice we have
one more tool and says if you're done
call this tool so this particular syntax
allows us to create an extra output on
the um on the so if I click this uh
thing it will pop out as an output and
I'll show you what to do here and as a
prompt we'll give it a very simple
prompt we'll just say hey just think
carefully and decide on the next step so
we've done now is we've taught an LM to
reason so let's hit update let's see
what happens with this little guy here
um you have do research right you have
four tools and suddenly you have done so
when we're done we're going to do
something with it but so we're going to
give this
context back to the thing but to make it
do some research what we're going to do
is we're going to Loop it onto
itself right what we're GNA because what
we're going to say is like hey this is a
multi-step research we're just asking
you to do one step but as the result as
the outcome there is a previous step and
so all it's going to do is just go on a
go onto itself and go and say am I done
if I'm done I'm going to call get get to
the writing the transcript otherwise I'm
just going to keep researching and just
keep going at it which is exactly what
we wanted to do and so now now that we
have this thing you have the con you
have the topic um you have the research
you have the right transcript report and
so now what we are basically having is
this really fun situation where yeah
this is this is this is now based on
some research so now if we give this we
we don't have to give it the brown in
motion we can give it like um I really
like this place called I
sandwiches um and so what what's going
to happen is it's going to try and
design the podcast setting as it usual
it usually does but then it's going to
go and start doing research and see it
does do research two research and did
two things of research and then came
back to the transcript and so what it
did is is actually invoked the tools and
and there you go between the bread the
only podcast blah blah blah blah blah
blah and so we're going to talk about um
I love and sandwiches I didn't tell it
that this is love and S this is
something it went in and searched the
internet and found and so it's like and
then you can see that I should the
person who founded this thing opened the
ike in this thing so all of this
information comes up so you can make it
now do like one of my favorite um Simon
[Music]
Willison AI slot
right and so now we can give it a topic
that maybe maybe brand new maybe
something that has not happened has is
not there not not exists in uh in the in
the parametric knowledge but now it's
based on a reality so we've built an AI
system that doesn't
just and there you go is we
can we can see
that it actually builds out really
interesting things from from this
research so if we look at the research
and actually look at what it does it
actually will you know go you
know and one it actually will search the
web and it will say I'm not collected
let let I will go get Google Search you
know and then it will do the function
call and do the all the things but we
don't have to think about it in
breadboard world we just like connected
the dots and things just worked because
what we've built is an an system that
does the ground research then writes the
Pod trans podcast transfer based on the
design design setting that we built for
but you know what we should not stop
here
because um now we're just having fun at
least I'm having fun I I can't hear you
so I'm hoping you're having fun say
something in the comments if you're
having fun um so I'm like every good
podcast has a cover art for their
episode right so maybe what we need to
do is we need to generate some cover art
for the thing and the The Way We Begin
Again is we're going to take our happy
little
model and what we're going to do with it
is we're going to make it um generate us
some podcast or some podcast art um in
in our uh in our system uh hang on a
second Let me refresh real quick there
you
go uh
so what we're going to do now is we're
going to
generate with this model we're going to
generate generate cover art prompt
because why bother building the um part
prompt art prompt ourselves when we can
just do this with with the AI and so uh
we will basically
say you are a prompt engineer who excels
at writing prompts for text to image
models given the podcast setting and
topic you are able to create prompt for
podcast cover art yeah bit bit hokey and
amateurish yeah with the name of the
podcast in big letters that seems right
um and then this The Prompt is going to
be fairly straightforward because what
we want is we want to have the knowledge
of the topic and the setting right we
need to have that information and
because we need to have that information
we are going to add this as parameters
to the model to this to the system and
so as you can see we have Topic in the
setting and so the setting is right here
so we're going to wire the setting the
topic is right here so we're going to
wire the topic so now we have the
generate uh cover art
prompt and also let's go ahead and I
recently built this really cool uh
generate image using IDE diagram API Del
is nice but I really like the Aesthetics
of um um ideogram so I'm just going to
use
that um and once I have that all I need
to do is I just need to combine the
transcript and uh the image into the
output and so to do this I'll use this
thing called a
Content that allows me to just
basically create a simple template and
says that
says um art goes
here uh
transcript goes here and U you will see
that now it has art and transcript
you're going to put art in here and then
instead of this line I'm going to build
it
here let's move it over
so and now we have a system that does so
if we give it I
sandwiches again hopefully fingers
crossed it will build us out an really
interesting uh system that will do a
little bit of research generate a little
bit of cover art um and from there it
will it will generation images takes a
little bit of time so um we will have to
wait a little bit and from there it will
give us not just a transcript but also a
fullon uh thing that you can present now
you can now share share is like this is
a full on U there you go between the
bread there's there's there's our thing
it has the podcast it has all of the
informations in it and
um as you can see we have our people
talking and there's interruptions
there's tension there's really
interesting things and at this point I
just wanted to kind of pose the question
to you and say if we view prompt
engineering really as an art of craft of
imparting wisdom what wisdom do you have
to
impart into the llm because there is or
do you know somebody who is really wise
and willing to impart it because we live
in an interesting New World the actual
utility of this really interesting
diffusion space um um um AI systems is
that we now can impart the wisdom and
embedded into AI systems we can
systematize wisdom um in for different
topics this thing can generate top
podcasts there could be another thing
that is really good at a problem
analysis that could be another thing
that's really good a system that's
really good at business research or
perhaps super forecasting uh all you
need to do is find the method the how
and figure out what is the right way to
impart that wisdom through a system of
prompts um into an llm nlm and create an
A system that does that interesting New
World suddenly English and philosophy
Majors might be uh more well positioned
to uh to do interesting stuff in the
space than than the the techies than us
Engineers because they're the ones with
the wisdom of how the world works and
perhaps more people could start gaining
um the value from that wisdom by using
the systems and I think that's what
makes it so exciting this this is what
like for me is the future and the most
interesting part about uh the llms it's
not I mean we will nail those
predictable cool customer service tasks
this will be done we will optimize our
way to it we will'll climb the crap out
of this but it's the things that are
able to predict the next Black Swan or
the next economic disaster and uh help
us see the things that we can't see
because it takes the stochastic quality
and the the all knowledgeable LMS
combines it with the wisdom and and
brings out something that we have not
seen before take multiple people
multiple personas take one problem
analyze it usually in a company like
deoe or something you would like spend
major dollars on it and basically you
would only have like three or four
analysis with LM suddenly we can do a
thousand of those and then we can have
LM sort and sift through that knowledge
and figure out what are some interesting
unpredicted um outcomes that we might be
interested and looking and that's the
stuff that's the that's the future right
that's the most amazing thing that's
what keeps me up at night thank you so
much I think I'm really really close to
uh to the end of the to the edge show
and um it looks like I timed it
perfectly too so you did well done well
played awesome thank you so much so
there's uh a couple of uh questions on a
similar topic which is around
um it's so fun to be able to just kind
of like iterate in this UI and like
build out these AI systems as an
engineer and a front end engineer
um can I like do boards as a service and
be able to just wire this up as kind of
part of my back end to play around with
this um and then do my own front end
that sits on top of it yes that's the
that's the vision of breadboard that's
really where we're going because what we
ultimately want to do is we don't want
to build a system where you build a
thing and then you have to rebuild it
again once you figured out this the the
the the pattern the AI system what we
actually want and today breadboard uh
has this concept of a board server that
if you host a board server every board
that is hosted on the server has an API
endpoint and so you can uh hit it and um
you basically as you make changes as you
push the changes into the into the
server you immediately get an API
endpoint and the way we're building it
is it's meant like actually if you dive
into deeply into this it's a very strong
object capability model designed for a
lot of distributed computing so it's
it's a highly highly distributed model
um you know me dude I I've built
component systems all my life so it's
like this was just one of those things
and so the vision of RedBoard is that we
don't want to build another thing that
you have to like okay I figured it out
now I have to write it code it's like no
once you've done with this you can just
take this and run with this and this is
the this is the system and you can
update it and you keep Keating keep
rebuilding you notice how it had inputs
and outputs these are the apis so you
can have the input this is your request
and
response got it and then how do I
evaluate let's say I want to like tweak
it and I've got version one versus
version two so to speak like yes so this
is this is also something that we're um
really really excited about I I can't
share much of this yet but uh the the
interesting thing is uh when you saw
this activity on the side this is
actually recorded as a run and so every
one of those runs is saved and stored
and so you can literally like basically
build a data set of runs of things that
you've produced and uh
and there is there is a way to
effectively evaluate and compare them
with each other and even do some hill
climbing on on top this thing got it
awesome that's really fun
um guy asked this asking about the
wisdom maybe prompt
templates you talked about the the board
server are there other ways to kind of
share this and yeah you can basically
share a board um you can share it as a
URL you can share it as an API endpoint
um and it's you can also turn it into
another component as you saw me pick out
ideogram guess what that ideogram is
it's just a pattern that is like that is
just an small board that I built that
it's again composability that's that's
my jam like decades and Decades of
experience of building comp composable
systems and and so it's all turtles we
like to say that in breadboard
everything is Turtles all the way down
like the everything is built from boards
and boards are built from capabilities
and the capabilities are very lowlevel
things that um like you can basically
say you know I think we literally have
like fetch like get get data from the
internet um or get access to the Secret
store and then um every everything is
built on top from from there got it and
then we're running out of time I know
but have there been boards that folks
have been creating that are doing more
like that was a creative task that are
doing kind of technical tasks and kind
of using it as a workflow engine yes um
it's it's it's really interesting
because um
boards I am very like you know you you
could tell that I'm swaying toward the
diffuse Point Cloud uh thing but there's
there's been folks who like really uh
narrowed zero in on like I just want
this precise mechanical task and usually
I say look if you don't have need to
iterate or move things around or mess
with stuff breadboard is probably not a
good fit for you if you already know
what you're doing you're fine you you
just write it on code where breadboard
strength is that is like you're you are
help you are going through this really
highly iterative process of trying to
understand how to impart a certain
wisdom into the system and this wisdom
does not have to be creative it could be
highly technical it could be uh anything
it's really the the litmus test is is is
going to require me to mess with the
prompts a lot got it figure out how how
this is going to work right thank you so
much Dimitri really appreciate it thanks
for showing us that thank you this was
fun yeah